http://www.evolvesports.com/privacy

Cookies provide several advantages to improve interactive services and make web browsing easier. By continuing to use this website you agree to our use of cookies.
More Information
Confirm
Shop Team Evolv
Resole Retail Store
Climbing
Climbing Shoes
Adaptive
All-Around
EVOLV®
Last updated 8 March 2018.  Effective immediately.
At Evolv USA, LLC, dba Evolv North America, we recognize the importance of our customer’s personally identifiable information or data (collectively the “personal information”) and privacy.  Evolv uses your personal information mainly to improve our products, Services, and advertising.  This Evolv Privacy Policy (the “Privacy Policy”) describes how Evolv and its parent, subsidiary, and affiliate companies (collectively “Evolv”, “we”, or “us”) collect, use, share, and store information through the mail, retail stores and wholesale accounts, Evolv.com and other Evolv websites that link to this privacy policy, and Evolv mobile services, including our mobile application (the “App”) (collectively the “Services”).
By visiting any Evolv Website (the “Websites”) or App, and/or by using the Services, including but not limited to, creating a Evolv account, purchasing and/or registering a product, downloading materials, registering for newsletters or updates, participating in an online survey, accessing customer care or warranty services, or by otherwise providing any personal information or data to Evolv, you agree to the policies described herein and to the Terms of Use, which are incorporated into this Privacy Policy by this reference.  Please review this Privacy Policy and contact us at info@evolvsports.us if you have any questions.
Collection and Use of Information
Personal Information.  When you access the Evolv Website or App, use our Services, or otherwise provide any personal information or data to us, we may collect, use, and store that personal information, including but not limited to your name, mailing, shipping and billing address, phone number, email address, contact preferences, activity interests, date of birth, gender, and credit card information.  We may also collect information that you provide to us about other people, for example, by purchasing gifts or products for family or friends, we may collect their name, mailing address, email address, and phone number.  The personal information we collect allows us and our marketing provider(s) to keep you posted on Evolv’s latest product announcements, updates, upcoming events, and Evolv news, and helps us to improve our products, Services, content, and advertising.  If you do not want to be included on our mailing list, you can opt out anytime by changing your account preferences or clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of the email.  From time to time, we may use your personal information to send important notices, such as communications about a specific sales or service transaction, our products, their proper use, purchases and changes to our terms, conditions, and policies.  Because this information is important to you, your use of Evolv products, and your relationship with Evolv, you may not opt out of receiving these communications.  We may also use personal information for internal purposes such as auditing, data analysis, processing payments and orders, and research to improve our products, Services, and customer communications.  If you enter into a sweepstake, contest, or similar promotion, or access linked social media accounts, we may collect and use the information you provide to administer those programs.  In addition, information that you give us may be combined with other personal information (e.g., order history, demographic data, etc.) from third-party sources to improve our products, Services, and programs.  For example, we may receive updated delivery and address information from third-party sources, which we use to correct our records and insure delivery of Evolv products and materials to you.
Our App uses the GPS feature of your mobile device to determine the location of the device, activities engaged in, and similar information. We and our third-party vendors or partners may collect and use this for purposes such as the functioning of the App, to make our advertising more relevant, and to improve our services.
Non-Personal Information. We may collect non-personal information, i.e., information that is not associated with a specific individual, from you when you visit the Websites and/or use our Services.  This information may include your Internet Protocol ("IP") address (which is the number automatically assigned to your computer whenever you access the Internet), browser type and language, Internet service provider (“ISP”), referring and exit pages, operating system, date and time stamp, and other data.  The IP address does not identify your name, email address, or other personal information.  We may use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, to administer our Websites, understand and analyze trends, learn about user behavior on the site, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.  We may also collect information, such as your occupation, language, zip code, area code, unique device identifier, location, and the time zone where our products are used so that we can better understand customer behavior and improve our products and advertising.  We also may collect information about how you use our Websites and Services from our other products. For example, some e-mail communications you may receive from Evolv Websites, Apps, and/or Services may include a clickable URL, which will automatically direct you to the Websites and collect non-personal information in the process. To avoid having your non-personal information collected, do not click on URL links presented in any Evolv electronic communications. Aggregated data is considered non-personal information for the purposes of this Privacy Policy.
We may also collect non-personal information through the use of “cookies” and other technologies such as pixel tags and web beacons.  A cookie is a file that is added to your computer so that the Websites can remember something about you, for example, to retain the contents in your shopping cart.  This helps us to better understand our customer’s use of the Websites and preferences, tells us which parts of our Websites our customers have visited and the frequency and length of such visits, helps us improve the appearance and functionality of the Websites, and measures and facilitates our understanding of the effectiveness of advertisements and web searches.  We treat information collected by cookies and other technologies as non-personal information.  When non-personal information is combined with personal information, we treat the combined information as personal information for the purposes of this Privacy Policy.  Cookies may remain on your computer after you log off the Websites.  By modifying your Web browser settings, you may refuse to accept cookies.  If you do so, you may not be able to access or use certain features of the Websites. For more information on the cookies Evolv saves, please visit,https://www.evolvsports.com/media/pdf/e8/69/6e/evolvsports.pdf.
Use of Information.  Financial and personal information that you provide is used to process your order, verify, bill, and collect payment for products that you order.  We may use your contact information from any order to send Evolv products, catalogs, emails, and other information about Evolv, its affiliates, and/or its partners.  If you register for evolvsports’s newsletter or mailing list and provide your email address to us, we will send you emails or other communications that may inform you of new products, special sales, promotional offers from Evolv, our affiliates, partners, Evolv news, and any other events or issues that we think you may enjoy or find interesting.  You may opt-out of receiving future mailings by following the steps described below in "Removing, Correcting or Changing Your Information".
Disclosure of Information to Third Parties.  Evolv does not disclose or share your personal information with other companies, persons or agencies, unaffiliated with Evolv, except as described in this Privacy Policy:
Service Providers:  Evolv shares personal information with companies and individuals who provide certain services for Evolv, such as information and payment processing, extending credit, fulfilling customer orders, delivering products, managing, analyzing, and enhancing customer data, marketing consultation and assistance, providing customer service, website maintenance and operation, assessing your interest in our products and Services, and conducting customer research or satisfaction surveys, etc.  These companies have access to personal information, including financial information, needed to perform their services or functions, are obligated to protect your information, and may be located wherever Evolv elects.
Partners:  Other than processing your order and payment and similar tasks, Evolv does not share your name and postal address with any non-Evolv affiliate, nor does Evolv share your credit card information or email address with any other third party.  Our customer's private, personal information and privacy is respected by Evolv.  Occasionally, Evolv may send information from our affiliates or partners to our customers that we think they may find interesting, in addition to communications directly from Evolv.
Lawful Requests:  Evolv may release your personal information: if it receives a lawful request through legal or administrative process, litigation, and/or from public or governmental authorities in or outside of your country of residence; to enforce or apply our Terms of Use and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Evolv, our customers, our employees, and/or others.  Evolv may also disclose information about you if we determine that for purposes of national security, law enforcement, or other issues of public importance, disclosure is necessary or appropriate.
Business Transfers:  In the future, Evolv may sell or buy companies, subsidiaries, business units, etc., and transfer or receive customer personal information as a result.  Such personal information remains subject to the provisions made in any pre-existing privacy policy, unless modified or the customer consents otherwise.  In the unlikely event that Evolv North America or substantially all of its assets are acquired, customer personal and non-personal information will be one of the transferred assets and will be subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy as it may be amended in the future.
Your Consent:  Evolv may disclose and use your personal information any time that you consent to such disclosure of use.
Third Party Analytics: Our website also uses third-party analytics vendors such as Google Analytics.  Please click here for more information about how data is collected and processed in connection with the Google Analytics service: www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/. We and our third-party vendors or partners use analytics data for a variety of purposes such as to improve the design and content of our websites, to help us learn things like what pages are most attractive to all of our visitors and what promotions visitors like to see, and to gauge the success of our advertising campaigns.
Interest-Based Advertising.  We may work with third-party advertising companies that collect and use information about your online activities across sites over time, in order to deliver more relevant advertising when you are using the Websites and/or Services. This practice is known as interest-based advertising. You may visit www.aboutads.info to learn more and to opt out of this type of advertising by companies participating in the Digital Advertising Alliance self-regulatory program. We do not operate or control this site and are not responsible for the opt out choices available there. Note that electing to opt out will not stop advertising from appearing in your browser or applications. It may make the ads you see less relevant to your interests. If you delete, block or otherwise restrict cookies or use a different computer or Internet browser, you may need to renew your opt-out choice.
Removing, Correcting or Changing your Information.  As a registered user, our Websites provide you with the choice to receive or decline most Evolv communications.  Except as otherwise provided herein, to elect not receive future electronic communications from Evolv and not have your information shared with other companies, or to correct or change certain information that you have previously provided:
You may log on to evolvsports.com as a registered user, access your account, and change or update your information and manage newsletter preferences.
You may send an email to info@evolvsports.us.
You may select the icon marked “Unsubscribe” at the bottom of any Evolv email, however, please recall that because Evolv maintains several individual contact databases, you may have to unsubscribe from each database individually.
Please note that, as stated above, from time to time, evolvsports may use your personal information to send important notices, such as communications about a specific sales or service transaction, our products, their proper use, purchases and changes to our terms, conditions, and policies.  Because this information is important to you, your use of Evolv products, and your relationship with Evolv, you may not opt out of receiving these communications. Further, Evolv will not delete personal information that is required by law or other ongoing legal obligations. If you would like to correct or request changes to the personal information that you have previously provided to us, please contact us at: info@evolvsports.us.
Protection of Personal Information.  Evolv is committed to protecting the personal information we collect.  While we cannot guarantee its security, we have implemented security procedures that we deem to be reasonable and appropriate to help protect the personal information that you provide to us. However, please understand that when you communicate with customer service via email or chat on our websites, these communications may not be encrypted, and we request ask that you do not share sensitive or personal information through email or chats. We may retain your personal information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law.
Information That You Post. When you use some Evolv Services or applications or post on Evolv Websites, chat room, or social networking service, the personal information that you share is visible to other users and can be read, collected, and used by them.  You are solely responsible for the personal information you choose to submit and publicize.  For example, if you list your name and email address in a forum posting, that information is public.  Please take care when using these features as this information is considered public information under this Privacy Policy.
Children.  Evolv does not knowingly sell merchandise for purchase by children.  If you are under 18, you may use our Websites only with the consent and involvement of a parent or guardian.  Our Websites and Services are not intended for the use of children under the age of 13 and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13.
Third Party Website Links.  Links to or from third party websites or social media provided on the Evolv Websites, App, and/or Services are provided as a convenience and you use them at your own risk.  Such third party websites and social media do not operate under this Privacy Policy.  Information, which may personal or financial information, location data, contact details, etc., may be collected by those third parties and such collection and use is governed by their privacy practices.  We encourage you to learn about the privacy practices of those third parties prior to using their websites or social media.
California Residents. Under California Civil Code Section 1798.83, California residents who have made a purchase from Evolv Websites within the past eighteen (18) months may request certain information regarding disclosure of personal information to third parties for direct marketing purposes. To request this information, please contact Evolv as provided below.
Changes to this Privacy Policy.  Evolv may change this Privacy Policy at its discretion at any time in the future.  If we change this Privacy Policy, we will post the revised Privacy Policy online.  We may notify you about material changes to this Privacy Policy by sending a notice to the e-mail address you provided to us, by placing a notice on our Websites, or through some other manner, at Evolv’s discretion. Please check our Websites regularly to see if this Privacy Policy has changed.
Questions? Please Contact Us. If you have any questions or concerns about the privacy or security of your information, you may contact us by email or mail at the following addresses:
You may send an email to info@evolvsports.us
You may send mail to the following address:
Evolv USA, LLC, dba Evolv North America
Attn: Customer Service3600 Pearl Street, Unit Boulder, CO 80301
